# 就跟漏斗一样
Like a funnel
# 搁在这里头
Put it in here
# 今天想给大家做一个素三角
Today I want to make a vegetarian Chinese samosa for you
# 看完这个在家就能制作
You can make it at home after watching this video
# 大大爷好
Hello Da Da Ye
# 二伯好
Hello Er Bai
# 素三角
Vegetarian Chinese samosa
# 老北京的传统小吃
Traditional Beijing snack
# 我跟您说实话
Let me be honest
# 我净听说过我还真没吃过
I have heard about it a lot but never tasted it
# 今天我得品尝一下
Today I get the chance to have a try
# 一会做好了请您品尝
Have a try after we finish cooking
# 传统的做法应该有焖子
Traditionally it should contain Menzi
# 就是用咱们的淀粉
Which is made from starch
# 绿豆淀粉跟薯类的的淀粉
Mix mung bean starch and potato starch
# 用1比5的水
Add 5 times of water
# 搁些酱油熬这个
Add some soy sauce and simmer (the slurry)
# 跟打糨子的似的熬成焖子
Simmer the slurry to cook Menzi, like making paste.
# 熬成焖子得晾凉
Cool it down after simmering the Menzi
# 那时间就过长了
It would take too long to make
# 所以我建议在家里头
So I recommend for home cooking,
# 如果有宽粉丝
you can use wide Fensi (vermicelli),
# 宽粉条也没问题
Wide Fentiao (vermicelli)
# 如果有凉粉也可以用
Or bean jelly
# 所以我们今天就采取了用凉粉
So today we will use bean jelly
# 它的原材料很简单了
The ingredients (of Chinese samosa) are fairly simple
# 胡萝卜我们就用擦子
We use food grater to shred the carrot
# 擦成丝
Into shredded carrot
# 用盐给它腌制一下
To cure it by salt
# 一小勺
One small spoon
# 直接就给它杀倒了
It works immediately
# 然后就听话了
to soften the carrots
# 增加底味
and add basic flavor
# 对
You’re right
# 腌10分钟
Cure for 10 minutes
# 好
Okay
# 这时候就把凉粉切上
Use this time to cut the bean jelly
# 切成小丁
Cut into small dices
# 大爷您知道为什么叫大大爷吗
Da Ye do you know why he is called as Da Da Ye?
# 王师傅要论起来
Talking about master Wang
# 是一个特别好的大哥
He’s a really amazing big brother
# 但是有一样要从业务上说
But professionally,
# 这也是算我们的前辈
he is a senior chef to us
# 因为王师傅大咱们七八岁呢
Since master Wang is 7 or 8 years older than us
# 七八岁呢那可不就是前辈了
7 or 8 years is not just senior
# 快一代人了
It’s basically one generation
# 而且在我们心目当中是一个好师傅
In our hearts he’s a good master
# 好大哥
A good big brother
# 就是我们的大大爷
It’s our Da Da Ye
# 切成小丁呢咬的时候啊
When it’s cut into dices,
# 口感也是好
The texture is good
# 它筋道
It’s chewy
# 咱们就用酱油拌它一下就行了
We simply add soy sauce and mix it
# 好吧
Okay
# 上面呢搁点酱油
Add some soy sauce on the top
# 为了找它的颜色
In order to color it
# 找颜色 提味
Coloring and seasoning
# 拌一下
Mix it up
# 再拿酱油泡上
Then soak in soy sauce
# 香菜切成末是吧
Mince the cilantro
# 香菜
Cilantro
# 这好香啊
This smells so nice
# 小葱花
Minced green onion
# 方方正正
Perfect square shape
# 盐一杀水出来了
After salted, we can squeeze out water (from the carrot)
# 它也踏实了不是扎扎拉拉
The carrots are soft and easy to manipulate
# 对
Exactly
# 我看大大爷每次做菜啊
Every time Da Da Ye cooks
# 每一个小细节都特别精细
He is so meticulous about every small detail
# 就让它
Just let it
# 讲究
Very careful
# 让它颜色也好看
Make it colored
# 红的绿的白的
Red, green and white
# 葱花还有芝麻啊
Besides sesame there’s green onion
# 再加上点这个焖子
And add some Menzi
# 这个不是擦完了吗
Isn’t this shredded?
# 再来两刀还是有点太长
Cut it a few more times cause it’s still too long
# 是吧
right
# 大大爷活细
Da Da Ye is very careful
# 那盆给您搁那边了
I put the bowl there
# 咱们就拿这个拌
We’ll use this to mix
# 把这个酱油呢篦出去
Leave out the soy sauce
# 咱们为了就让这凉粉有颜色
What we did is only for coloring the bean jelly
# 有味道了
And seasoning
# 去掉水分
Leave out the water
# 要是真是在家咱们要做的话
If you want to do this at home
# 没有这个
Without this
# 咱们就用宽粉条
You can use wide Fentiao (vermicelli)
# 宽粉条也是
Even wide Fentiao (vermicelli)
# 在火上
On fire
# 搁个葱姜搁个大料瓣
Put green onion, ginger and garlic minces
# 把那粉条咕嘟一下
And boil with the vermicelli
# 它有味了
Until it’s seasoned
# 这个基本上就行了
Then it’s considered done
# 一会咱们做的时候
Afterwards
# 再一和
Mix it up
# 下一步咱们就开始和面
Next step we will knead dough
# 面有两种
There’s two type of dough
# 像回民的他们都是用冷水面
HuiMin use cold type of dough
# 今天咱们就用冷水面去做
Today we will use cold type of dough
# 有的汉民是搁上肉的
Some HanMin’s dough has meat on the top
# 他是用烫面
They use hot type of dough
# 汉民用烫面
HanMin use hot type of dough
# 这两种有些不同
These two are slightly different
# 跟大家说一下
For your information
# 250克的面
250 grams of flour
# 125克的水
125grams of water
# 放水要均匀
Water should be well-distributed
# 你看大大爷和面
Look at Da Da Ye kneads the dough
# 一边和这盆都特别光溜
The bowl is very smooth on the surface
# 三光面光手光盆光
The dough, his hands and the bowl are very clean
# 就得和成这样
This is how dough kneading works
# 干完活哪哪都干净
It’s clean even after the kneading
# 就一定要让它干净
It should be clean
# 面基本上就行了
Dough is almost complete
# 你看看就这点水和这点面
Only using this little water to knead the dough
# 我们要求这样
This is what we required
# 饧一饧
Let the dough rest
# 饧了一下
After resting
# 再揉一下
Knead it for a while
# 这面滋润了
If the dough is moist enough
# 面还真白
The dough is so white
# 和面和的就匀
Kneading will be well-disturbed
# 所以饧的就快
So it only need a short time to rest
# 饧会儿
Rest for a moment
# 这马上就下剂儿啊
After the resting it’s complete
# 咱们这时候把馅儿和好
We mix the stuffing now
# 这个再搁点盐来点味儿
Put some salt for seasoning
# 咸中有味淡中鲜
It’s a salty but umami taste
# 搁到胡萝卜上
Put it on carrots
# 你一会怕其他的再杀出汤来麻烦
Since we don’t want salt to cure other ingredients
# 这个呢
This one
# 葱花搁上
Put in green onions
# 葱花搁上完了之后呢
After green onions
# 撂上香油
add sesame oil
# 一般我们拌馅也是这样
Usually we mix ingredients like this
# 香油要浇到葱上
Make sure the sesame oil was pour on the green onions
# 它是有味
It has flavor
# 香油浇在葱上
Pour sesame oil on green onions
# 原来是没有搁味精
In the past we don’t put gourmet powder
# 为了提鲜
For umami taste
# 我们现在还搁点味精
We put some gourmet powder now
# 味精现在让使了
It is permitted now
# 让它更香点
Makes it more aromatic
# 我们给它拌起来
We mix it together
# 把这个都拌在一块
Mix all these toghether
# 吃的这鲜啊这汁儿
The juice is so umami
# 这时候把香菜再搁里头
Now it’s time to put the cilantro in
# 瞧这红得绿的颜色好看
There’s red and green so pretty
# 香味出来了
Aroma is appearing
# 最后把芝麻搁上
Last put in sesame
# 这个都是炒好的芝麻
These are sesame that has been stir-fired before hand
# 更香
More aromatic
# 行了现在开始包
Okay let’s make them
# 这馅儿闻着就香
The stuffing smells so nice
# 揪成呢
Make it into
# 将近5克
Nearly 5 grams
# 5克重的剂儿
5 grams of dices
# 你拿个秤随便约绝对一边重
Take a scale
# 行了
Okay
# 干面不能太多
Don’t add to much flour
# 干的太多
Too much flour
# 一会儿它粘不上了
It will not be sticky enough
# 跟鸭饼似的那么大就行了
Big as a duck cake
# 够薄的
So thin
# 过两天我做一个准备向大大爷交一作业
I will try it as a homework assignment
# 大爷这个劲我看有点像小学生似的
Da Ye’s strength is like a kid
# 大大爷我也做一个
I will try it as well
# 跟你交作业了
As a homework assignment
# 这个没问题这个一看就会
No problem this is easy
# 这个三角怎么做
Way to do samosa crust
# 弄上水在中间
Draw a line of water in the middle
# 中线给画上印
Marked the middle line by pressing slightly
# 为什么用这个水
Reason to use water
# 它粘得住啊
Is because it’s sticky
# 画好了之后呢
After drawing
# 折成1/2
Fold it in half
# 你瞧这样
look
# 拿擀面棍一轧中线
Sightly press in the middle by a rolling pin
# 拿刀 走
Cut it by the mark
# 这弄完了之后呢 你瞧
Look
# 这个也成三角了
This became a triangle shape
# 这个呢就这条线
This line
# 一定要在中线给它兜起来
Must be seal at the middle
# 就漏斗一样
Like a funnel
# 搁在这里头搁完了之后
After putting the stuffing in
# 这儿一捏
Give it several pinches right here
# 你看没有
Look
# 轻轻一捏这也好做
Slightly pinches
# 封上就行
Make sure it’s sealed
# 这要吃咖喱味的黑椒味的
Curry or pepper flavor
# 什么味都行
Is acceptable as well
# 搁一鲍鱼也行
Even an abalone
# 对鲍鱼也行海参
Yeah, abalone or even sea cucumber
# 把葱烧海参放在里边
Put braised sea cucumber with scallion
# 好
Okay
# 倒油
Pour oil in
# 炸三角看看啊
Look at these Chinese samosa
# 均匀饱满 皮儿薄馅儿大
Stuffing are even and plentiful in a thin crust
# 每个跟一个艺术品似的
Each one is like a work of art
# 是吧
Right
# 有很多东西可以工业化生产
There are many things that can be produced industrially
# 但是这像这类的食品
But dishes like this
# 工业化生产很难
Is very difficult to produce industrially
# 五成的油温
Heat the oil in 120-180 degree Celsius
# 分两锅炸
Fry in two different pans
# 一定要炸成金黄色
Must fry it until the crust turn gold
# 你看起来了
Look it flows
# 珍珠小泡啊
There are small bubbles like pearls
# 好嘞
Done
# 这油温正合适
This oil temperature is just right
# 这个得六七成热
These are 60-70 percent done
# 小荷包似的
Like small bags
# 为了一块成熟
In order to finish them at the same time
# 这个一块回一下油
Put these old ones back to the pan to heat for a while
# 关火
Turn off the fire
# 好嘞 出锅啊
Okay it’s done
# 好
Okay
# 看看
Take a look
# 粉丝朋友们啊
Fans
# 筋道了 馅儿亮
Stuffing are so chewy and colorful
# 外头酥啊
The crust is so crispy
# 这焖子到嘴里面的感觉滑爽
The Menzi taste smoothly
# 然后香菜那种香气
And the aroma of cilantro
# 外皮那种酥脆
With the crispy crust
# 人间美味啊
Taste like heaven
# 我吃到了4种香味
I ate four types of aromas
# 第一外皮酥脆
First the crisp of crust
# 香菜的香 葱香 芝麻香
Aroma of cilantro, green onion and sesame
# 还有胡萝卜的香
And carrots
# 一个字 香
Aromatic
# 大大爷做这个
Da Da Ye’s
# 炸三角
Chinese samosa
# 这就是人生五味
These are the five tastes of life
# 生活就是这么简单
Life is that simple
# 希望网友们看完在家就能制作
Wish you guys could try this at home after watching this video
# 这个是最大的好处
This is the biggest benefit
# 谢谢大大爷
Thanks, Da Da Ye
# 大大爷您辛苦了
Da Da Ye has worked very hard
# 对于还没有入行的学生
For students who have not yet entered career life
# 想做厨师
If you want to be a chef
# 应做好哪些准备和选择
What are some preparations and choices
# 有利于日后的发展
That will helps afterwards
# 其实作为一个将要毕业的年轻人
Actually being at your stage
# 想做一个厨师
Wants to be a chef
# 其实我觉得要从兴趣开始要培养
I think you should make cooking as your hobby
# 觉得有兴趣了
If you truly find it interesting
# 当走入这个行业的时候
While entering this career
# 要认准这个行业
You must believe in this career and work consistently
# 应该说它叫勤行
Becoming a chef needs diligence
# 比较辛苦
It’s hard
# 要做好吃苦的准备
Need to prepare for its difficulties
# 然后从兴趣到热爱这行
From interesting to enthusiasm
# 要拿出一定的时间
It costs some time
# 是吧
Right?
# 这个行业我们可能会早起晚归
It may require us to get up early while back home late
# 工作比较繁忙劳累
Works are busy and tired
# 时间也比较长
Plus, long duration
# 这样要做好这方面的准备
Need to prepare for these challenges
# 对自己的打磨的时间
Practicing and improving yourself
# 要将近要有
Will nearly needs
# 少则也要七八年
Seven to eight years at least
# 多则得十几十多年
Ten or more years if longer
# 要认准要做好思想准备
Need to be sure that you wants to be a chef and prepare mentally as well
# 像人家说
People says
# 说现在所谓的吃苦
That difficulties nowadays
# 不是以前所谓的体力上的吃苦
Isn’t just hard work physically as the past
# 主要是各方面
It appears everywhere
# 包括受气
Including being bullied
# 比如自尊上面能隐忍
Or need to hide your pride
# 这方面都算吃苦
These are also count as difficulties
# 是吧
Right?
# 因为这行业来了以后
Because once you entered this career
# 基本都是师父的言传身教
Basically, you learn from your master
# 加上自己的一些磨练
Plus some practice by yourself
# 比如说练练刀功
For example, improving your knife skills
# 业余时间可以练练翻锅
Practicing food tossing in a wok in your spare time
# 是吧
Right?
# 因为我们烹饪当中的
Because when we’re cooking
# 食材很多
There’s a lot of ingredients
# 我们还有一步一步的要认识它
We need to know them step by step
# 了解它
Understand them
# 所以如果经不起这些磨难
If you can’t stand these difficulties
# 经不起这些历练
Can’t go through
# 可能会半途而废
It is possible that you will give up